<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experience on</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/</link><description>Recent content in Experience on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Senior Software Engineer</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/quantcast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/quantcast/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building and scaling distributed backend systems processing high-volume real-time traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving reliability and performance of critical services through architectural and operational improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Driving initiatives to simplify system design and reduce operational complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentoring engineers and improving engineering practices across teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tech Lead</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/money-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/money-view/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led &amp;amp; mentored a cross-functional team, collaborating closely with engineering, product, design, and marketing to develop scalable, multi-platform products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architected &amp;amp; developed a scalable integration platform enabling sourcing partners to connect with the lending system, reducing partner onboarding from one month to a few days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a scalable data pipeline for tracking &amp;amp; analyzing events across platforms, cutting event tracking costs by 96%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Led development of a rule-based system that pushes in-app updates to Android devices in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drove organization-wide adoption of distributed tracing, reducing mean time to identify production issues from 30 minutes to under 10 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Platform Engineer</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/treebo-hotels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/treebo-hotels/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; architected dockerized ELK for log aggregation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; implemented an automated RabbitMQ cluster to improve messaging reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivered technical talks on Docker and Docker Compose best practices and integrated them into multiple applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built tools to measure IT performance metrics such as lead time to change, frequency of releases, change failure rate, and mean time to recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a system for monitoring and tracking JIRA tasks and RCAs, reducing engineering time spent on incident management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced teams to load testing best practices, improving system load capacity and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Senior Software Engineer</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/bigbasket/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/bigbasket/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; developed a priority order flow for members, improving retention by 30%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated third-party systems for end-to-end last-mile delivery, improving operational efficiency by 80% and reducing costs by 40%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed a dynamic banner engine for the website, boosting promotional engagement by 20% and e‑voucher redemptions by 15%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built core logic for calculating delivery charges across multiple order types, improving accuracy by 15%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed an algorithm to display products based on local availability, increasing conversion by 25%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Associate Analyst</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/manhattan-associates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/manhattan-associates/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Associate Analyst with the Slotting Optimization R&amp;amp;D team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>