<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experience on</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/</link><description>Recent content in Experience on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backend Engineer — Money View</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/money-view/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/money-view/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working as a part of the Growth Team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; developed a platform, that is used by our partners to integrate with our lending system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with cross-functional teams including engineering, product, design &amp;amp; marketing to build scalable products for different platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a scalable data pipeline for tracking all the events across different clients &amp;amp; servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; developed an engine that can push an in-app update to the android app based on rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Platform Engineer — Treebo Hotels</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/treebo-hotels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/treebo-hotels/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; architected dockerized ELK for log aggregation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; architected automated dockerized RabbitMQ cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave tech-talk on Docker and Docker-compose best practices and incorporated them in multiple applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed &amp;amp; developed tools to improve business performance:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Serverless framework to auto-generate 3P reports weekly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built tools to measure IT performance metrics: lead time to change, frequency of releases, change failure rate &amp;amp; mean time to recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incident Alerting: Enhanced monitoring and tracking of the JIRA tasks and RCAs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PgBouncer clustering: Designed the connection pooling for AWS RDS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduced teams to Load Testing best practices and helped them in load testing their applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked with other developers, QA teams and peers to design and develop automated solutions and tools for monitoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about the performance all the time, and proactively work to make our platform better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planned and architected secrets management strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Full Stack Developer — BigBasket</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/bigbasket/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/bigbasket/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked as a part of product and features development team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed a priority order flow for members. This feature allows exclusive access to promotions, evouchers, and priority slots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used AWS Lambda for digitally signing PDF Invoices for customers. (For GST)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated with third party eSodexo to allow an easy payment flow for members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated testing using python selenium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked on stored procedures to provide optimal execution for routine scripts that were less performant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated third-party API for the entire last-mile delivery for BigBasket. The solution gives an integration to cater to the last mile routing, tracking of delivery vehicles, and reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated with third-party logistics (delivery services) Bike Ninja and Shadowfax, with BB backend for delivering small orders and express orders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a feature for stocking products in a warehouse in the most optimal way, this solution increases the picking efficiency, reduces replenishment requirements and maximizes throughput by determining the best slot locations for all products in the DC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed a portal for order allocation using Backbone.js for frontend and python for the backend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed the banner engine for the website. Provided a feature to link banners to other entities in the database, displaying banners based on the entity&amp;rsquo;s availability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed and developed core logic for handling delivery charges for different types of orders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked on an algorithm to display products specific to the customer’s locality based on the product’s availability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Associate Analyst — Manhattan Associates R&amp;D</title><link>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/manhattan-associates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://adityamisra.github.io/experience/manhattan-associates/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During internship built:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order Management System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This system the tracked the complete lifecycle of an order. It was completely developed on a C++ platform &amp;amp; oracle database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated Single Sign-On&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The project involved the implementation of two processes Authentication and Authorization. It was completely developed using Java &amp;amp; oracle database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked as an Analyst with the Slotting Optimization R&amp;amp;D team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>